Hello my name is Mary.
This pattern is extremely useful but we
need to construct complicated objects
with a long list of variables in the
constructor method. Let's work through
the concept with an example from the
popular Demon Slayer. Imagine you
are a swordsmith that works for the Demon
Slayer Corporation. There are so many
members in this corporation and each of
them needs a . Sadly, your village
is short of labour and a vast amount of
order is coming in. You desperately need
a more efficient method to craft those
swords. For those who have no idea
what a Nichirintou is, here are some
examples. So, what
should you do to meet the demand from the
Demon Slayer Corporation. Here comes the
Builder Design Pattern. The Builder
Design Pattern is one of the creational
design patterns. It aims to separate
the construction of a complex object from
its representation so that the same
construction process can create different
representations. And this is a good
choice when there are too many arguments
in the constructor or parameters to be
initialized in the object class. The
Builder Design Pattern also allows us to
create different types of objects using
the same Builder Interface. The Builder
Interface is an abstract interface for
creating parts of a Product object. It
includes the steps for construction that
are common to all builders. The
Concrete Builder Class provides the
different implementations of construction
steps. Product Classes are the
resulting objects. Director Class
gives instructions to construct the
objects using the Builder Interface.
Finally, for the Client Class, they send
the order to the Director and indicate
what objects they want. Sounds
complicated, right? No worries, we will
go through this bit by bit. As a
swordsmith, the final products are
Nichirintou and Saya, which is the
scabbard of the Nichirintou. In the two
classes, I specify the elements that
constitute a Nichirintou and Saya, with
the getter methods in them. Setter
methods are not stated here as we want to
separate the construction process from
the classes. You can see it as the goods
only, instead of creators. To code the
setter methods, we create a Builder
Interface to put those in. Then, we set
up concrete Builder Classes to craft the
Nichirintou and Saya, with the names of
NichirintouBuilder and SayaBuilder. These
concrete builder classes implement the
Builder Interface and return the products
with the getResult method. The
concrete builders are similar to the
workers to get the goods manufactured.
They follow the working protocol, which
is the Builder Interface to finish their
jobs. Up till now, we don't have the
places to input our desired specs for the
Nichirintou and Saya. To do
so, we set up a Director class. This will
specify the steps and parameters to be
put into the Builder Interface. You can
consider this class as the boss that
orders its workers to build on different
things. But the boss won't tell his
employees to work for no reason. There
must be a client to send an order to the
boss. Thus, it's time for the Application
class. As the clients are the ones that
are most clear about what they want, they
point to some objects and request the
boss to do it. They can get the output
once the workers finished building them.
The Bulider Design Pattern can be treated
like this diagram for easier
understanding. After we run the codes, we
successfully crafted the Nichirintou for
Tengen Sama and Inosuke, also the Saya
for Tanjirou. If we want to make more
Nichirintou and Saya, just put more codes
in the Director and Application Classes.
Now we finished our job and can take a
rest, thanks to the Builder Design
Pattern. Hope you have a better
understanding on the Builder and give it
a try in the project. Enjoy your
learning! Thanks for watching! Here are
some references I used. Feel free to take
a look. Thanks.